{
    "id": "211cdc38c2854f148309893605d8b308",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "………………………… they live here?",
            "description": "Have is followed by the past participle are is followed by an ing form do is followed by the infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "Have",
                "Do",
                "Are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… the door when you leave.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperatives. ",
            "answers": [
                "Lock",
                "Locking",
                "Locks"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you …………………………… talking to him.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after would rather to refer to the present or future. ",
            "answers": [
                "stop",
                "stopped",
                "have stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked if we ……………………………. our food.",
            "description": "Present perfect becomes past perfect in the reported speech.",
            "answers": [
                "ate",
                "have eaten",
                "had eaten"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. care of his health.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "does not take",
                "do not take",
                "is not take"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither of these answers ………………………………. right.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after neither or either.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Marconi ………………………….. the radio.",
            "description": "Use the simple past to simply say that something happened. ",
            "answers": [
                "has invented",
                "invented",
                "had invented"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked if he …………………………….. home.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can go",
                "could go",
                "could to go"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He is used to …………………………… hard.",
            "description": "The to in used to is a preposition. Use an ing form after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "working",
                "worked"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Iron …………………………… in many countries.",
            "description": "Is found is the passive form of find. ",
            "answers": [
                "is found",
                "has found",
                "found"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "While he was walking across the field, he ……………………………. by a snake.",
            "description": "Was bitten is the passive form of bite.",
            "answers": [
                "bite",
                "was bitten",
                "bitten"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She would rather starve than ………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "beg",
                "to beg",
                "begging"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}